# Zexi Liu

- 0405 502 802
- Bellamark, NT 0832 (willing to relocate)
- ieffliu2802@hotmail.com

  ightarrow

  igh
- in <a href="https://linkedin.com/in/zexi-liu-0934841b3/">https://linkedin.com/in/zexi-liu-0934841b3/</a>
- https://Github.com/JeffLiusGitHub
- https://portfolio-add7c.web.app/

### **About**

I am a passionate and quality-oriented developer, experienced in web development, especially front-end development with JavaScript, Typescript, React, HTML and SQL. An effective communicator and a good team player with can-do attitude. As a developer, I am attentive to every detail with good time management. I am also a quick learner, willing to keep up with the new technology. I am currently pursuing a career with engineering opportunities in a full-time capacity.

## **Experience**

### Openpay Group Ltd (Australia) Frontend Developer

Apr 2022 - June 2022

#### Responsibilities:

- Add new content in the share packages within the Monorepo by react and typescript
- Develop website with dynamic information for forms, using Formik and Yup for validation
- Add the carousal function to the landing page
- Edit curve and flat header for different devices
- Generic bug fixing
- Learned network security knowledge for example: SQL injection, XSS, CSRF, session fixation, etc
- Write test based on react testing library

## Ablink Pty Ltd (Australia)

Nov 2020 - Oct 2021

### React Developer

### Responsibilities:

- Worked as a front-end developer by using React
- Used HTML, CSS, JavaScript, react to create the responsive website
- Designed the website by using responsive design pattern
- Fixed the bugs to improve the website performance
- Conducted Cross-platform browser test and unit test on the website
- Controlled the website version and collaborate with teammates via Git
- Exceptional attention to detail for modifying CSS into every pixel

### **Topsek Technology Ltd (Shanghai headquarter)**

Nov 2019 - Feb 2020

### **Data Visualizations intern**

# Responsibilities:

• Liaised with customer on-site for enterprise system security

- Installed Linux system CentOS as the server
- Used Linux Shell to set up the server
- Installed the client applications on users' computers
- Set up the Linux server to receive logs
- Visualised the data on Splunk

# JuneYao Airline (China) Aircraft Electrical Engineer

Jul 2014 - Jul 2017

#### Responsibilities:

- Performed basic hand skill, standard trade practices
- Planned and organised aviation maintenance work
- Applied quality standards applicable to aviation maintenance processes
- Effectively accomplish the high workload on daily bases
- Ensure safety and security of aircraft and operations
- Troubleshoot emergencies by using the Aircraft Maintenance Manual

# **Projects**

# Cycling Injuries Prevention Website Asp.Net Developer (Mar2020 - May2020)

### Responsibilities:

- Designed the website UI mock-up on Adobe XD and structure with MVC model
- Coded the frontend with Asp.net framework. HTML, JavaScript and CSS
- Did the usability testing and debug the website
- Followed by agile methodology and Git

### Website link

- Toy Robot Simulator (React, Redux, Styled-component, Material UI) <a href="https://tinyurl.com/53ffpchu">https://tinyurl.com/53ffpchu</a>
- Shopping Website App (React, Redux, MUI, animation-on-scroll) <a href="https://Tinyurl.com/yc8pz38f">https://Tinyurl.com/yc8pz38f</a>
- Real-time chat App (React Node.js Socket.io): https://bit.ly/3t8afr5
- KanBan Board App (React Material UI): <a href="https://tinyurl.com/2vvy8e9m">https://tinyurl.com/2vvy8e9m</a>
- News Page based on json data (React CSS) https://tinyurl.com/r3u9c8az
- Tour Website Demo (HTML, SASS): https://bit.ly/3hZwrww
- Sportholic cycling injury preventing website (HTML CSS JS ASP.net): https://cutt.ly/AbCihoJ
- Promotion videos for this project: <a href="https://bit.ly/3e7sq80">https://bit.ly/3hVN4cu</a>
- Jeff Meal Website Demo (React CSS): <a href="https://bit.ly/3C5eWmX">https://bit.ly/3C5eWmX</a>
- Auth Demo (React Firebase Authentication): https://bit.ly/3k7ZQ9W
- Quote Website Demo (React Router): <a href="https://bit.ly/39hJVA1">https://bit.ly/39hJVA1</a>
- To-do List (TypeScript): <a href="https://bit.ly/3C6EZu1">https://bit.ly/3C6EZu1</a>
- Flat Curve header, Carousal, enter-driver-licence page(Typescript, React): <a href="https://bit.ly/3lNa7bP">https://bit.ly/3lNa7bP</a>

### **Data analysis**

Analysed the correlation between different factors and predicted salary of Australian IT professionals using statistics. (Result link: <a href="https://github.com/JeffLiusGitHub/dataAnalysis">https://github.com/JeffLiusGitHub/dataAnalysis</a>)

# **Technologies**

Developing Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, Python, Android developing

 $We bsite\ development:\ React,\ HTML,\ CSS,\ Redux,\ ASP.NET,\ Node.js,\ React\ testing\ library$ 

Database: SQL, Oracle SQL developer, no-SQL, Mongo DB, Cassandra, Neo4j, AWS

Data Visualisation: R studio, Tableau

Design Tools: Photoshop, Premiere, After Effects, Adobe XD

Methodology: Agile development

## **Education**

Master of Information Technology

Jul 2018 – Jul 2020

Monash University

 $\ensuremath{\clubsuit}$  Bachelor of Electrical Engineering and Automation

Civil Aviation University of China

Sep 2010 - Sep 2014

## Referee

Available upon request